AZEEM AMANAT

Summary

I have 6+ years of experience in software development. I am expert in ASP.NET MVC and writing store procedure. My expertise also includes the responsibility for daily operations of the projects.

Skills

- JavaScript, JQuery, Web API
- AJAX. Angular js, Store procedure, C#
- NET Framework, Entity Framework
- HTML, CSS, JSON
- ASP . NET Web Forms
- SQL Server management and Visual Studio
- SVN & Oracle

Experience

NETSOL TECHNOLOGIES (Senior Software Engineer) 1/2017- Present

Providing technical services to develop and maintain the application

- Development and bug fixation in POS module.
- Trouble shooting and Issue Identification.
- Impact Analysis and unit testing.
- Client communication for business related queries and share root cause against production issue.
- Production support in the case of business urgency.

XAMEER TECHNOLOGIES (Software Engineer) 6/2015 - 12/2016

Responsible for the unit testing, code review and bug fix of allocated modules.

- Using Entity Framework & LINQ queries and Data access layer.
- Developed Web application in Asp.Net/MVC Razor using Web APIs.
- SQL scripting and stored procedure development.
- Database Restore and SQL Jobs

Accounts Management System (Accountex)

Accountex is a powerful accounts management system that provides complete control over your account management solutions. Its comprehensive feature set includes account creation, fourth level accounts management structure, vouchers, transactions, trial balance and financial reports.

Custom Duty Management System (Custom Clearance)

Custom Clearance is a web based application for managing clearing agent business. Customer's files can be logged, updated and searched and tracked through dashboards on few clicks.

School Management System

It is a Complete Software which provides account management solutions for School. It's a web based application which works on centralized database.

Job Portal (PIRA)

Job Portal is a complete software solution for manpower recruitment agencies. It provides all recruitment process for Recruitment Company.

FUTURE NOW TECHNOLOGIES (Software Engineer) 9/2013 - 5/2015

- Work as Offshore development team member.
- Maintenance and customization of existing application.
- Unit testing, bug fixing against client issues.

Loyalty Ware Application

Loyalty Ware is a CRM application outsourced by Brierley Partners. This CRM has multiple clients like GameStop, Hard Rock, American eagle, Money Gram, and Levis, etc.

Technologies Used: C#.Net, ASP.Net 4.0, Oracle 11g.

International Policy Administration System (IPAS)

It is desktop software to manage insurance policy. IPAS cover all functionality needed to run insurance domain. User can add the policy and make transaction and Installment plan (monthly, yearly, and quarterly).

Education

- B.S (Hons) Computer Science 2008-2012
- FSc (Pre Engineering) 2006- 2007